# [ Bells Chiming ]#...
...What a beautiful old man.
What a lovely head.
India is filled with old men, memsahib.
But not like the one in the yellow turban.
He's like a head of John the Baptist.
The memsahib refers to the storyteller?
Are these silent monsters
at peace with us?
It is but a truce they keep with man.
But I, who have seen their tusks
stained red with blood -...
...I could tell you a tale of the silent ones.
For a few coppers? Eh?
Yea, for a bowl of rice?
What would you do with my image,
memsahib?
I would keep it...
for a memory of India.
Verily, you would have
all India in your picture.
Nay, you would have the book
Of the jungle to read in my eyes.
In the beginning, you must think
Of nothing but silence -...
...a silence so vast that the ear can hear it.
[Man Continues]
Great trees like the pillars of the temple...
...- with ferns like green
carpets underneath.
[ Birds Chirping ]...
...While above, under the dome of heaven
Where lived the winged ones...
...the wind moves restlessly,
Whistling across the roof of the world.
These are the eaters of grass
In a world of torn flesh.
[ Birds Continue Chirping ]...
...Early the little fawns
Must learn their lesson__...
...feet that make no noise,
eyes that see in the dark...
...ears that hear the leopard leaving his lair.
For the leopard lives by the law
Of claw and horn and fang...
...He will kill for hunger and eat thereof...
...but he will never kill fork killing's sake ...
...a law all men break.
but the jungle folk obey.
[ Growls ]...
...[ Growls ]...
...[ Elephant Trumpets ]...
...These are the lords of the jungle.
The tribe of Hathi, the silent ones.
They go their way, eaters of grass
In a world of carnage.
[ Trumpets, Growls ]...
...[ Growling Continues ]...
...[ Loud Exhaling ]...
...For the wolves are the true
hunters of the jungle.
And like huntsmen,
They stick to their Clan...
...with a strict regard
For hunting Calls and tribal law.
Free Companions of the woods, they may
Fight and quarrel amongst themselves...
...until the strongest of them wins
The leadership of the pack.
[ Snarling ]...
...Yet jungle folk say...
...the wisest amongst them
is the tribe of Baloo, the bear.
[ Chittering ]...
...He is a teacher of the jungle law.
Yet there is one who knows law__...
...the barrel-bodied mugger,
the Crocodile...
...with his chin in the shallows
And lust in his cold heart...
...hoping to drag down to the depths
All who wander along his river bank.
[ Roaring ]...
...[ Roaring ]...
...And in the legends of the jungle
There is a black prince...
...shrewdest of the lords of claw,
Horn and fang...
...As bold as a buffalo,
as reckless as a wounded elephant...
...with a voice as soft as wild honey
Dripping from a tree.
Unbridled, unmastered, unafraid.
Bagrheera the black panther.
- And now__
- [ Shrieks ]...
...- Behold, the villain of my tale.
- [ Growling ]...
...The killer,the man-eater...
...the assassin who first brought murder
to the jungle Clans.
Shere Khan, the tiger.
[ Roars ]...
...It is said that in his first kill__...
...when he was Cain to some
Poor Abel of the glades __...
...when he ran from the scene of his crime...
...the trees and creepers
Whipped him with their branches...
...and striped his yellow hide
with the mark of Cain.
[ Growling ]...
...This evil lord must have his dish-lickers...
...his bullies for attendants.
Tabaqui the jackal.
And the hyena__...
...hungry for the scraps
Of their murderous master's feast.
[ Hissing ]...
...But my tale is not alone
Of outcasts and heroes.
I will tell you also of the snake, Kaa,
the wise one...
...the oracle who taught Mother Eve
The speech men use...
...for trickery and sin.
What is the book of life itself
but man's war with nature...
...the struggle between village and jungle,
[ Birds Chirping ]...
...Under the mantle of wild creepers
And great trees...
...many a ruined City lies forgotten
in the pages of time.
Yea, where a thousand war Chariots
Proclaimed the might of a great king...
...before whom all men bowed their heads.
Nothing remains but a trellis
For wild figs to sun upon.
But what of the great maharaja,
The loser in this battle?
He has left many such a palace
To his Cousins, the monkey folk.
- The bandar-logs __
- [ Chittering ]...
...The outcasts of the jungle.
[ Chittering Continues ]...
...First you must picture me
as I was, milords -...
...Buldeo, the mighty hunter.
It was a long time ago...
...and very far away...
...on a summer's evening
in the Seeonee hills.
- Ajao. Ajao.
- [ Horn Blowing ]...
...[ Shouting In Native Language ]...
...[ All Chattering ]...
...Again some palaver.
Its Buldeo, master.
That fool would make speeches
the whole day.
[ Object Clatters ]...
...- Come, Durga. Let, s listen to him.
- [ Object Clatters ]...
...- [ Horn Continues ]
- Ajao.
[ Crowd Chattering ]...
...You cannot build your houses
just anywhere.
[ Chattering In Native Language ]...
...We have to plan out our village.
- [ Chattering Continues ]
- Someday there will be a mighty city here.
[ Chattering Excitedly]...
...A mighty city with marble houses.
The temple shall be there,
facing the marketplace.
That’s where I wanted the bean patch.
No that’s for the marketplace,
as Buldeo says.
And the barbershop will face the temple.
I shall find someplace
for the bean patches anyway-...
...outside your mighty city.
Go Durga. Take the child
and the old man to the cart.
[ Axe Striking ]...
...Nathoo.
Come Grandfather.
Did you hear that?
We’re going to have a marketplace
and a temple and a mighty city.
Aye we’ll have all that
If we can beat the jungle.
But have you and your hundred years
seen man win a war with nature?
Sit here Grandfather.
There Nathoo.
Now.
[ Growling ]...
...Go back to your work.
[ All Chattering ]...
...[ Growling Snarls ]...
...[ Sobbing ]...
...Nathoo?
Where are you my baby?
[ Sobbing Continues ]...
...Rao. Look. Our little Nathoo,
he has wandered away.
Now don’t worry Messua.
The child couldn’t go far.
I’ll look for him right away.
Durga you search in there.
Nathoo.
[ Growling ]...
...- [ Durga ] Nathoo.
- Nathoo.
Nathoo.
- [ Tiger Snarls ]
- Nat -...
...[ Roaring ]...
...[ Screaming ]...
...- [ Roaring ]
- [ Screaming ]...
...- [ Screams ]
- [ All Shouting ]...
...[ Man ] Buldeo.
Tiger. My husband.
Rao.
Abdullah. Singh.
Abdullah. Ali. Mohammed. Singh.
[ Messua ] Tiger.
[ Gasps ]...
...[ Shouting ] No.
No.
[ Sobbing ]...
...[ Roars ]...
...[ Roaring ]...
...[ Sobbing ]...
...- [ Men Chattering ]
- Poor master.
Poor Messua.
Let us all go and look for the child.
All men bring your spears.
Ali Singh Abdullah. Torches.
Follow me.
[ Buldeo ] Nathoo.
Nathoo.
Poor little baby. Poor little Nathoo.
- And that poor mother.
- Poor mother
Is it every woman who can have
a wolf nurse her baby for her?
Do you believe that Subahdar?
Oh yes memsahib.
And His Excellency your father,
has many records...
...of wolf children from the Indian hills.
- It is true.
- True?
In the beginning was it not written...
...that the she-wolves
loved the children of man?
Were not the wolves the foster parents
Of many a child in India?
Little naked and bold...
...the man's Cub entered the wolves’ Cave.
Ahai.
He felt just as much at home with the cubs
as at his mother's side.
[ Man ] Nathoo.
- [ Men Chattering ]
- Nathoo.
[ Man In Distance ] Nathoo.
[Buldeo Narrating]Lost and tired,
he fell asleep among his
brothers of the jungle.
Akkela the father wolf,
And Rakksha the mother wolf...
...knew that Shere Khan is prowling outside
Looking for the man Cub.
[ Whimpering ]...
...So they took him into their family.
[ Man ] Nathoo.
He grew up with the cubs.
They called him Mowgli - the Little Frog.
Father wolf taught him his business
until every rustle in the grass...
...meant just as much to him
as to his brothers the wolf cubs.
All the lords of the jungle
became his friends.
He had only one enemy-
Shere Khan the tiger.
- [ Murmuring ]
- Did Mowgli live to hunt Shere Khan?
Did he live? Oh.
But had I known then what I know now.
Twelve years had passed...
...and Shere Khan was on the trail
Of the wolf boy.
[ Growling ]...
...[ Roars ]...
...[ Growling ]...
...[ Shere Khan Growling ]...
...[ Snarls ]...
...[ Growls ]...
...[ Roars ]...
...[ Growling ]...
...[ Crocodile Roars ]...
...[ Sheep Bleating ]...
...[ Horn Blowing ]...
...[ Horn Stops ]...
...[ Cattle Lowing ]...
...[ Horn Blowing ]...
...[ Horn Stops ]...
...## [ Mandolins ]...
...# See the silver moon #...
...# Hear the breezes croon #...
...#Jungle’s cradle tune #...
...- # Lulla lullaby#
- ## [ Vocalizing ]...
...# Now the darkness swings #...
...# Down on velvet wings #...
...#While our river sings #...
...- # Lulla lullaby#
- ## [ Vocalizing ]...
...# Sleep sleep up above #...
...# Stars keep watch with eyes of love #...
...# Sleep sleep baby hush-a-bye #...
...## [ Vocalizing ]...
...# Sleep sleep eyelids close #...
...# Dreaming dreams of pearl and rose #...
...# Sleep sleep baby hush-a-bye #...
...## [ Vocalizing ]...
...# Saw the silver moon #...
...# Fear the breezes croon #...
...#Jungle’s cradle tune #...
...# Lulla lullaby#...
...## [ Vocalizing Ends ]...
...[ Sniffs ]...
...[ Howls ]...
...- [ Men Clamoring ]
- [ Mowgli Barking ]...
...[ Clamoring Continues ]...
...[ Mowgli Yelps Barks ]...
...[ Mowgli Yelps ]...
...[ Yelps Shouting ]...
...[ Clamoring Shouting ]...
...[ Mowgli Barking ]...
...[ Barking ]...
...Wait. Wait.
Let me handle him.
[ Clamoring Stops ]...
...[ Clamoring Shouting ]...
...[ Mowgli Growling ]...
...Buldeo. Buldeo.
- [ Barks ]
- Ow. He bit me.
He is a wild boy.
Cover him up. Cover him up.
[ Chattering ]...
...[ Yelping Panting ]...
...- Who are you boy?
- [ Chattering In Native Language ]...
...Can’t you hear?
[ Whooping ]...
...[ Howling ]...
...Give me a torch. A torch.
Give me that torch.
[ Gasping ]...
...This boy has never seen fire before.
He’s from the jungle.
- Yes he is a wild boy.
- [ All Murmuring ]...
...We must be kind to him. Release him.
Release him?
Are you mad?
This is a thing of the jungle.
[ Messua ] Let me look. Let me look.
Look at the scars on his arms and legs.
Those points on his bones -
He has run on all fours... with wolf cubs.
Poor child.
This boy has been reared in the jungle.
He has the evil eye.
[ All Murmuring ]...
...I begin to think he has.
Moonshine.
I think this boy is Messua's little baby
which was stolen that day we built the wall.
Could this boy be your's Messua?
No. He's not mine.
But he's a handsome boy.
Eyes like red fire.
Any woman would like to have
a son like him.
But my Nathoo was soft and plump.
But, mistress, how could he be plump
running naked in the woods?
I warn you all. He has the evil eye.
- [ All Murmuring ]
- [ Messua ] No, Buldeo.
He is some poor, lost lad -
though not my own.
But I am a lonely woman,
and if you would let me...
...I will shelter him for some other woman
who has lost her son.
He is a wolf.
Let one in, and all will follow.
- He will bring down the jungle upon us.
- [ Shouting, Murmuring ]...
...What the jungle has taken,
The jungle has restored, Buldeo.
[ Pundit ] Aye. Aye.
Take this boy into thy house my sister.
And out of your little hoard of money,
forget not to honor me...
...for I have saved his life on this day.
- [ Man ] Release him.
- Wait.
Are you going to turn this devil loose
before I can protect you?
A gun.
- Buldeo -
- Don't -...
...A gun.
Buldeo.
Now release him.
[ Mowgli shouts, Growling ]...
...No.
No.
- Boy.
- [ Growling ]...
...Boy.
Will you come with me?
Come.
[ Growling ]...
...Oh. It's, It,s all right.
Come on.
Come along. Come.
Come.
It's all right. Come along. Come.
It's all right.
Down upon our heads
even before the temple...
...we have called the curse of the beast.
[ Murmuring ]...
...No more shall we prosper.
The wild pig will trample down our vines.
The tiger will stalk our streets.
[ Murmuring ]...
...We have opened our doors to the devil.
...Don't look upon evil.
Mahala. Get home to bed.
At least I can keep my own daughter
from harm.
[ Growls ]...
...[ Dog Barking ]...
...[ Mowgli Grunts ]...
...- Get back, Kpota.
- [ Barking Continues ]...
...Is that anyway to treat
one who has come to live with us?
[ Barks ]...
...[ Sniffing ]...
...I remember the day I gave
the first little shoes to my Nathoo.
[ Lapping ]...
...[ Growls ]...
...[ Growling Continues ]...
...Wolf- Uh, wolf boy.
Uh -...
...Oh, those feet have never worn shoes.
No, you are not my son.
But you look very much like my son Nathoo.
Nathoo called me 'Mother'.
[ Slowly] 'Mother'.,
'Mother'.,
[ Slowly] M - Mother.
Uhh.
And what did the wolves... call you?
[ Slowly] Wolves.
[ Howls ]...
...[ Howls ]...
...[ Howling Continues ]...
...M -...
...Mowgli.
Mowgli?
A little frog?
Yes, you were like a little frog to them,
the beasts of the jungle.
[ Chuckles ] And so you are Mowgli to me.
Come.
Come on.
[Buldeo Narrating]
For months and months after that night...
...Mowgli was busy learning the ways,
Language and customs of men.
- [ Cattle Lowing ]
- [ Bells Clanging ]...
...[ Mowgli Shouts Twice ]...
...- [ Cattle Lows ]
- [ Mowgli Shouts ]...
...- What are you doing?
- [ Gasps ]...
...You are like a little panther.
I thought someone had found
the hiding place.
- Hiding place?
- Mm-hmm.
- What is this?
- Money.
What is it for?
What is money for?
To protect us from hunger and cold.
It lives in a hole like a cobra?
[ Laughs ] No.
If we need a bag of rice, I give these
to the merchant in the square.
He gives us the rice.
- What a fool that merchant must be.
- No.
Will the Man-Pack give us
anything for this?
Yes.
Will Buldeo give me a tooth?
Tooth? You have all your teeth.
No. A -A sharp tooth.
Oh, a knife?
Yes. A knife tooth, like a tiger’s knife.
What need have you for a knife?
To sink it in the throat of my enemy.
Your enemy? Ha. You talk about
Akela, the father wolf...
...and Raksha, the
Mother wolf, and how much...
...better it is in the jungle
with all your friends.
Now who could be your enemy?
Shere Khan, the tiger.
Tell Buldeo to sell you a knife.
Give him the money.
I shall have a tooth.
- I shall have a tooth.
- [ Laughs ]...
...[ Footsteps Approaching ]...
...My father says I mustn’t speak to you.
What happened to him?
[ Mahala ] My father shot him.
We missed you six moons ago.
He was Baloo’s cousin.
He had no man for an enemy.
But my father kills every bear he sees.
Why?
Because he is a great hunter.
He kills them even when he’s not hungry?
Hungry? We don’t eat bears.
Then why did he bring him here?
To show how brave he is.
And my father was very brave
to kill that tiger.
[ Chuckling ] That old tiger?
He lived on lizards and rats.
He was too old to hunt rabbits.
He must have died in his sleep.
I see. You could kill the bear
and the tiger with one shot.
I kill Baloo’s cousin?
I’ve gone fishing with him.
Fishing with a bear?
How can a bear bait a fishhook?
He looks in the river,
he sees the fish he wants, then who.
He knocks it out.
Didn’t I tell you not to speak
with this thing?
I told Messua to keep you
away from this house.
Messua sent me here to talk to you.
She sent me to get a tooth.
A tooth?
Yes. This is the tooth I want.
Put that knife down
before I send a shot through you.
And then you would put my head
on the wall...
...like the old Khan there.
But I would spring as I die
and give this tooth back to you.
Now, now.
You’re not in the jungle, boy.
No.
No, I am not in the jungle, Buldeo.
I am with the Man-Pack,
but I am not a man.
What are you, boy?
I was until now a cub.
But now I have my tooth.
I can run with the jungle as I please.
I am a wolf.
If you had a knife...
...would you go back to the jungle?
The knife is yours for two annas.
Messua gave me three.
One, two, three.
There. Three is more than two.
Yes. More than two.
Now get out of my house.
[ Dog Barking ]...
...[ Bell Clanging ]...
...See, Shere Khan?
- ‘Tis for you - deep in your throat.
- Mowgli.
Won’t you be afraid
to go back to the jungle?
Afraid of the jungle? Why?
I’m of the wolf pack.
They are my friends.
Then why did you buy the knife?
For Shere Khan, the tiger.
This is for him.
He drove me out of the jungle.
He went away far off...
...but he swore he would lay my bones
in the river when he returned.
- [ Cow Lows ]
- I also made a little promise.
I have told the wolves I would kill him.
You can speak their tongue?
You can speak to animals?
Can you talk to Rama, the great herd bull?
Rama is a dumb slave.
He has been with the Man-Pack so long...
...he cannot talk to anyone.
[ Mahala ] Can you speak to him?
[ Chittering ]...
...[ Chittering ]...
...[ Chitters ]...
...What did he say?
Don’t you know what the monkey people
always say?
'We, the monkey people,
are the greatest folk in all the jungle.
We know this is true
because we always say it is true.
Mowgli, will you let me
Hear you talk to the wolves?
Yes.
Tonight when the moon rises.
[ Distant Howling ]...
...[ Howling Continues ]...
...- Are you afraid?
- No.
Let’s go.
[ Howling ]...
...[ Wolf Howling ]...
...[ Howling Continues ]...
...It’s a wolf. What did he say?
[ Howling Continues ]...
...Wood and water.
...Wind and tree.
[ Howling Continues ]...
...Jungle favor go with thee.
You have been given the favor of the jungle.
[ Mowgli ] We be of one blood -...
...you and I.
[ Wind Howling]...
...[ Wind Whispering]
We be of one blood, you and I.
Come, Mowgli. Come.
Come. Come.
Ahai, Hathi.
[ Growls ]...
...I am with the Man-Pack now.
See, I have my tooth -
as sharp as a tiger’s tooth.
[ Trumpets ]...
...He said Shere Khan is far away...
...but I had better take care and hide
when he comes back here.
Hathi, will you warn me
when he comes back to our jungle?
[ Trumpets ]...
...Thank you, brothers.
Then we shall see whose bones
will be laid in the river.
[ Trumpeting ]...
...[ Rain Pattering ]...
...Hold on. Tight.
[ Yells ]...
...[ Elephant Trumpets ]...
...[ Growling, Snarls ]...
...Bagheera.
Mowgli.
[ Snarls ]...
...[ Growling ]...
...Your claws are sharp and strong.
But not as good as mine.
Look.
[ Snarls ]...
...Who is man that I should
care for his ways?
Brown digger, eater of earth.
I am Mowgli of the jungle,
back in the night.
Now that I have my tooth,
who shall stay me when I strike?
Mowgli, come back.
I’m afraid.
[ Bagheera Growling ]...
...[ Snarls ]...
...[ Birds Twittering ]...
...[ Chittering ]...
...There.
Mighty hunters,
greater than your father...
...who killed everything
until the jungle killed them.
Why did they go away?
Why did I go away?
Because I was a man cub,
afraid of a tiger.
The jungle knew I was afraid
and cast me out.
[ Chittering ]...
...This was the king’s palace.
King?
What is a king?
Oh, Mowgli. You know so much,
and yet you know so little.
This was a great walled city...
...a city with hundreds of elephants
and thousands of horses...
...and thousands and thousands o fmen.
And it all belonged to a great king.
[ Animal Hooting ]...
...And where is this great king now?
[ Echoing ]
And where is this great king now?
[ Chittering ]...
...[ Monkeys Chittering ]...
...Where is he now?
[ Echoing ] Where is he now?
[ Shrieks ]...
...Mahala?
[ Echoing ] Mahala?
- Mahala?
- Mowgli. Mowgli.
[ Mahala ] Here I am.
Mahala, are you hurt?
No, I’m all right.
[ Rattling ]...
...The king’s treasure chamber.
Look.
The emeralds.
Pearls.
This is like the stuff I gave Buldeo
for my tooth.
The stuff that passes from hand to hand
and never grows warmer.
Only this is yellow, and that was brown.
[ Hisses ]...
...[ Mowgli ] Let’s get back to the light.
These pebbles are no good to eat.
[ Coins Rattle ]...
...There is nothing here. Nothing.
[ Hissing ]...
...[ Cobra ] Am I nothing?
Father of cobras, we be of one blood,
you and I.
She’s only a little cub from the Man-Pack.
She means thee no harm.
Who art thou with the knife
and the snake’s tongue?
Mowgli, they call me.
I am of the jungle.
The wolves are my people.
Father of cobras, who art thou?
I am the warden of the king’s treasure.
The great king built the stone above me
that I might teach death...
...to those who come to steal.
Three times the stone
has been lifted by thieves.
Look at thy feet.
The thieves are still here.
[ Hisses ]...
...But I am no thief.
[ Cobra ] Indeed.
[ Hisses ]...
...Be still, Mahala. Be still.
[ Cobra ] Oh, no, boy.
Let her run to and fro a while.
Let her make some sport.
The others did so until I touched them.
Then they whimpered a while...
...sighed and were still.
- Kill him, Mowgli. Kill him.
- [ Cobra Grunting ]...
...[ Cobra Growling ]...
...Kill him?
- [ Cobra Grunting ]
- Don’t be afraid.
Look. Our father of cobras is so old,
he has outlived his poison.
[ Hissing ] Kill me. Kill me. Kill me.
I am ashamed.
There has been too much talk of killing.
Come, Mahala. We’ll go now.
[ Cobra Hissing ]...
...Keep that silly treasure.
But I’ll take this.
I can use it to prod Rama with.
Look at the ruby, Mowgli.
You could buy hundreds of villages with it.
Aye, boy. Thousands of villages.
Take it with thee.
But see that it does not kill thee at last.
[ Hissing ]...
...Kill me? This stone?
Yes. I have outlived my poison...
...but that ruby holds more death
than all my tribe.
It will kill and kill and kill...
...for killing’s sake.
My strength is dried up,
but this stone will do my work.
It is death, it is death, it is death.
But take the ruby if thou wilt.
Nay, father of cobras. I believe thee.
We shall go as we came.
[ Cobra ] Aye.
Ye be wise to take no death with thee.
May I take just this one piece, Mowgli?
Keep it if you like.
Get up, lazy bones.
I dreamed I was a princess
in the city of the great maharaja.
Get up.
There’s no fire in the grate,
and there is no rice here.
But it was not a dream.
I saw the great king’s city.
Get on with you.
Enough of this talk.
Dream?
This is no dream.
Maybe I am dreaming.
This is pure gold.
Who gave this to you, my darling child?
The white cobra.
Cobra?
Yes.
I did not want the diamonds.
Diamonds?
Nor the big ruby.
Big ruby?
This big.
Where? What nonsense is this?
Where is this room - this ruby?
When did you go there?
Whose gold is this, Mahala?
The great king’s gold.
In the treasure chamber
Of the king’s palace.
I tell you, Father, Mowgli said
I might keep just this one.
Mowgli?
You have been in the jungle?
Last night Mowgli took me there.
But, Father, you will not hurt him?
I would not harm a hair on his head.
But you must never let anyone
know about this.
Not a living soul, do you hear?
Yes, Father.
[ Coin Rattles ]...
...[ Rattling Continues ]...
...[ Coughing, Wheezing ]...
...[ Coughing Continues ]...
...[ Footsteps Approaching ]...
...Good morning, Buldeo.
Good morning.
I-I can’t take you now, Buldeo.
It’ll be at least another hour.
[ Buldeo Mutters ]...
...Now wait a minute, Barber.
There-There is no river between us.
Oh. Oh, my- my poor leg.
[ Stammering ]...
...Uh, uh -This lumbago is killing me.
I can’t go around with half my beard cut.
Ooh. Th-This lumbago is terrible.
I - I-I can hardly bend my knee.
What makes you tremble
like wash upon a line?
Now you keep out of this, Buldeo.
If I cut him, he-he doesn’t have to pay.
- Y-You want to cut me?
- No, no.
Now listen here, barber.
I’m not a man to be shorn
like a sheep in the midst of a brawl.
- Barber-
- I want -...
...- Barber?
- Hmm?
Move your left foot.
Well, uh -...
...[ Scoffs ]...
...I said the left foot.
Oh, oh, the-the l-l-l-l -...
...l-l - left.
Left.
[ Stammers ]...
...- This foot.
- [ Gasps ]...
...Excuse me, Buldeo.
You are standing on my money.
- Your money?
- I saw it first.
- [ Barber Stammering ]
- Jackals. [ Chuckles ]...
...- It’s mine.
- There’s no need to quarrel.
- There?s enough for all.
- Where? Where?
There’s a lost city... in the jungle.
- You have found a treasure.
- Where?
Shh. Do you want to tell the whole village?
Not a word now.
My daughter found it with the jungle boy.
[ Lows ]...
...[ Bird Twittering ]...
...[ Panting ]...
...[ Low Growling ]...
...[ Louder Growling ]...
...[ Animal Hooting ]...
...[ Sniffs ]...
...[ Growls ]...
...[ Animal Whooping ]...
...[ Growling ]...
...[ Growling Continues ]...
...[ Whooping ]...
...[ Trumpeting ]...
...- [ Bells Clanging ]
- [ Lowing ]...
...[ Howling ]...
...[ Screeching ]...
...- [ Growling ]
- [ Animal Whooping ]...
...[ Trumpeting ]...
...Tiger’s coming.
Up, you dumb ones. Up.
[ Trumpeting Continues ]...
...Up. Ho. Ho. Ho.
Ho. Ho. Ho.
- [ Animal Whooping ]
- [ Quiet Growl ]...
...[ Louder Growl ]...
...Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho.
Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho.
Ho. Ho.
[ Bells Clanging ]...
...[ Loud Growling ]...
...- [ Agitated Shouting ]
- [ Mowgli ] Tiger. Tiger.
- Th-Th-The -
- Tiger.
To the temple. To the temple.
To the temple.
- [ Shouting ]
- To the temple, all of you.
Shut the gates. Shut the gates.
[ Horn Blowing ]...
...[ Horn Blowing Continues ]...
...[ Man ] Tiger. Tiger.
- Quickly, Little Frog, to the temple.
- No. Not I.
- I have my tooth.
- No, no. Don’t go. Don’t go.
Mowgli.
[ Howling ]...
...Wait.
Don’t go. He will kill you.
No. I shall bring back his yellow hide.
Mowgli.
Where is your son, Messua?
Where did he go?
Stop him. He has gone after the tiger.
Oh, that bragging of a child.
Don’t be impatient, Buldeo.
He’ll be back.
Suppose the tiger should kill him.
Ooh, what a tragic calamity.
No, no, we must save him.
We must bring him back.
How kind you all are
to comfort me this way.
He really is a sweet boy.
I knew you would come to love him.
Love him? I wish I had a boy like him.
Now, don’t worry.
If he’s not back in a short time,
I’ll track him to the ends of the earth.
[ Animal Hooting ]...
...Kaa.
Kaa.
[ Groaning ]...
...I want to sleep.
Go away.
[ Hissing ]...
...I have to talk to you.
Who are you?
Can’t you see, Kaa?
What does the Law of the Jungle say?
We be of one blood -...
...ye and I.
Ye come.
[ Hissing ]...
...Ah.
It is a manling.
It’s I, Mowgl, Kaa.
The Little Frog...
...the one that used to throw stones at me?
I was a cub then, Kaa.
You called me a flat-headed earthworm.
Forgive me...
...for you are a wise, old, strong...
...and most beautiful Kaa.
True.
I am beautiful.
Yes.
Now that I am a man,
I have a tooth.
I wish to pull the whiskers of death.
The striped one?
You know all things?
I know that Shere Khan has killed...
...and eaten...
...and now sleeps by the bamboo.
Tabaqui the jackal told me so...
...uh, before he passed on.
Tabaqui?
Yes, indeed.
Here he is.
How may I slay his master, Kaa?
He’d kill you with one blow.
Let us go upstream.
Hold on, little brother.
Shere Khan is nothing but a big cat...
...and all cats fear the water.
But Shere Khan will not follow me
into the river.
Since you’re a man...
...use your cunning.
And if I made him angry, Kaa...
...will he follow me into the river?
If he will not catch you first.
[ Mowgli ] Thank you, wisest of all.
[ Kaa ] Go on.
I’ll wait for you here.
Wish me good hunting...
...O wise, strong and most beautiful Kaa.
[ Kaa ] Good hunting.
[ Growls ]...
...[ Roars, Snarls ]...
...Good morning, Shere Khan.
Did I wake you up?
You hunter of worms...
...you striped cattle thief.
- Don’t sneak away.
- [ Roars ]...
...Coward.
You mangy yellow dog.
Come back.
[ Snarling ]...
...Can’t you jump?
Are you too old, you frog eater?
Fish killer.
[ Roaring ]...
...I’ll get your hide today.
No, no. I won’t come down.
You come up to me.
Get this.
And this.
- [ Shouts ]
- [ Roars ]...
...Bah.
- [ Shouts ]
- [ Loud Roar]...
...Come on, Shere Khan. Catch me.
[ Roaring ]...
...[ Roars ]...
...[ Growling, Roaring ]...
...[ Hissing ]...
...- This is getting dangerous.
- Yes.
Maybe there are tigers
waiting for us in this tall grass.
All right.
Stay here.
[ Animal Screeching ]...
...[ High-pitched Howling ]...
...[ Animals Howling, Whooping ]...
...[ Elephant Trumpets ]...
...Shere Khan is dead.
I have killed Shere Khan.
[ Animals Whooping, Growling, Howling ]...
...What if he finds the boy
and tears the secret from him...
...and-and then says he didn’t find him?
You’re right.
We cannot trust him.
Uh, you go first,
and I’ll protect your rear.
You go first,
Go on.
By the Bull that bought me,
I made a promise -...
...a little promise.
Only thy coat is lacking
before I keep my word.
Come, Shere Khan.
Lend me your coat.
You won’t need it anymore.
You don’t need to shoot, Buldeo.
I have killed him.
Look at him.
This is the end of a very old war.
Hmm. You have killed him.
You found him there.
I killed him with my tooth.
He is mine.
Who are you to tell me what is yours?
Get up, boy.
You took my daughter
to the jungle last night.
You took her to a lost city.
Come on.
Take me to the treasure chamber.
I will not take you, Buldeo.
The Lost City is a city of death.
The treasure is death.
- I will never take you there.
- Come on, jungle brat.
Come on, or I’ll shoot you.
- Go ahead and shoot.
- You scum of the wolf cave.
- [ Roars ]
- [ Rifle Shot ]...
...I-I hope he didn’t shoot the boy.
No. No.
That’s a sign for us.
[ Growling, Snarling ]...
...[ Growling Continues ]...
...[ Roaring ]...
...Change back to a man...
...and spare my life.
Spare my life, Mowgli.
[ Roaring Continues ]...
...[ Gasps, Moaning ]...
...I did not know you were anything
more than a herd boy.
May I rise up and go away...
...my lord?
Get up.
Go. Tell Messua that Mowgli
has avenged her man.
He has killed Shere Khan
and will bring home his yellow hide.
Maharaja.
Look.
- Great king.
- [ Laughing ]...
...Go on.
Maharaja.
- Maharaja.
- Great king.
- Tell me the secret too.
- Tell me too.
[ Barber]
They say there’s enough for three.
- [ Pundit ] Great king.
- [ Buldeo ] Great king.
Three old vultures.
- Go back to your village.
- Yes, milord.
[ Mowgli Laughing ]...
...- Ma - Maharaja.
- My king.
- Where -Where is the treasure?
- Go back to your village.
- Maharaja. Great lord.
- [ Laughing ]...
...Here. Here, you.
- Did he tell you the secret?
- Come on. Where’s the treasure?
Do – Don’t try to cheat us.
The boy told you where to go.
Boy indeed.
Didn’t I tell you the first time I saw him
he was a witch?
I saw him with my own eyes
change himself into a black panther.
[ Chuckles ]
Come on, Buldeo. No tricks now.
If you try to cheat us, we’ll change you
into something worse, I swear to you.
[ Low Growling ]...
...Get down, Bagheera.
Stop their quarrel.
[ Snarls ]...
...[ Buldeo ] The boy turned himself
into a black panther before my eyes.
He is a witch, I tell you.
I must warn the village.
- Buldeo -
- Here.
I still think you’re lying,
and I’ll soon find out.
[ Roaring ]...
...[ Bells Clanging ]...
...Ho.
Ho.
Come, Shere Khan.
Look at Buldeo, the mighty hunter.
Ho.
Now go get him. Get him.
- What have I done?
- [ Man Shouts ]...
...Why do you stand there gaping so?
Gather branches. Build a fire.
Remember, he must have
a chance to confess.
Yes, the three of us
will deal with him alone.
We’ll deal with him all right.
[ Drum: Steady Rhythm ]...
...[ Gong Clanging ]...
...[ Wolf Barking ]...
...[ Howls ]...
...- [ Gong Clanging ]
- [ Drum Continues ]...
...- [ Man ] Clear the way.
- [ Howling ]...
...[ Gong Clanging, Drum Beating
Grow Louder]...
...[ Barking ]...
...[ Mowgli Howling ]...
...[ Howls ]...
...Buldeo, we are ready.
Bring the witch-boy.
Well, boy?
Witch or devil, whatever you are...
...you heard them.
They are ready.
One last choice -...
...the secret or the fire.
[ Messua ] Buldeo.
Buldeo.
[ Sobbing ]...
...Let me talk to him.
Let me talk to him.
Good.
You talk to him.
I will leave you alone.
He won’t tell.
I think we’ll have to burn him.
Then we would never find the treasure.
We’ll burn him...
...but not now.
The boy will lead us to the Lost City first.
Nathoo, my little son...
...why won’t you tell them the secret?
Never will I take them into the jungle.
But they will set you free -...
...free to live with me.
- Live with you?
- Aye.
I have a jungle mother too...
...and these two things
fight together in me...
...like the snakes fight
together in the spring.
I was a wolf.
The jungle cast me out.
I am a man.
The Man-Pack cast me out.
But you have killed Shere Khan.
You can go back to the jungle.
Aye, you can be lord of the jungle.
No.
I have nowhere to go...
...but into the Red Flower- the fire.
No.
But it does not matter.
The jungle will know from Bagheera
that I have killed Shere Khan.
No. The jungle will know from you, Mowgli.
See? Here is your tooth.
Mother.
Watch, watch, watch, watch.
- See them’
- He’ll escape.
Are you also too dumb to see it?
Of course. He’ll escape,
and then we’ll follow him to the treasure.
That’s right.
You two go to the edge of the jungle.
Wait there and mark his trail.
Go.
Your time is up.
[ Crowd Shouting ]...
...[ Shouting Continues ]...
...It’s the mother witch who freed him.
- Get her.
- [ Crowd Shouting ]...
...Wait. Wait.
- Messua is no witch.
- [ Shouting Continues ]...
...But Buldeo is a bad -...
...Tie both of them until I return.
[ Animal Whooping ]...
...Buldeo. He entered by this tree.
He never suspected we let him escape.
[ Buldeo ] Don’t say that.
See?
There is his trail.
[ Animal Whooping ]...
...[ Whooping Continues ]...
...[ Loud Whooping ]...
...I’m – I’m frightened.
Hmm.
There’s nothing to be afraid of.
We have our guns.
[ Loud Whooping ]...
...Let’s go.
We can’t be very far away.
Listen, brothers.
I have planted tracks for them
as deep as an elephant’s.
[ Snarling ]...
...They will be here soon.
Quiet, you grinning black shadow.
- [ Growling ]
- Quiet, gray brother.
This is not our kill.
- Look, look.
- Look.
[ Animal Whooping ]...
...- Wait for me.
- Not so fast. [ Chuckles ]...
...[ Buldeo Cackling ]...
...- [ All Cackling ]
- [ Monkeys Chittering ]...
...I will be the maharaja.
[ Echoing ] I will be the maharaja.
[ Echoing ] I will be the maharaja
Of this mighty city.
I will be the chief of all the temple.
[ Echoing ]
I will have all the barber shops.
[ Echoing ] I will have all the barber shops.
[ Laughing, Echoing ]...
...Let’s look for the treasure.
[ Echoing ] Let’s look for the treasure.
You look over there.
[ Hissing ]...
...[ Stammering ]...
...Uh - [ Stammering Continues ]...
...Look.
- I found it. I found it.
- [ Laughing ]...
...[ Buldeo ] He found it.
Come on. He found it.
Wait for me.
[ Echoing ] Wait for me.
[ Buldeo ] He found it. Come on.
- [ Barber Cackling ]
- [ Pundit Echoing ] Wait for me, Buldeo.
- Let us go in there.
- Let us go in.
I-I - I found it.
I - I claim the right of first choice.
That’s right. You deserve it.
He goes first.
- [ Chortling ]
- I’ll help you.
Help yourself. I’ll help you.
[ Chortling Continues ]...
...[ Hissing ]...
...[ Stammering ]...
...Shoot. Shoot.
Sh-Sh - Shoot.
Don’t – Don’t shoot. Don’t shoot.
Shoot. Shoot.
No, no. Don’t – Don’t shoot. Don’t.
Pull me out. Pull me out.
Pull me, Shoot, will you?
Pull me up.
[ Coins Rattling ]...
...You missed him.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven -...
...A million.
[ Laughing ]...
...[ Laughing Continues ]...
...I’ll never have to count again.
[ Laughing ]...
...[ Laughing ]...
...Maybe we’ve been cheated.
It’s gold. It’s gold.
It’s the mother and father
Of all the rubies in the world.
Where’s my royal turban?
[ Laughing ] They’re all pure gold...
...and they’re all mine.
I shall walk upon gold.
I shall eat upon gold.
I shall use gold for a coverlet.
[ Laughing ]...
...- Give it to me.
- Give it to me.
- It’s mine.
No. Are you mad?
Shall I bash your heads in?
- Give it to me. I had first choice.
- No, it’s mine.
- The old cobra was right.
- [ Arguing Continues ]...
...First, they go mad.
Don’t forget, Buldeo, we are two to one.
I want that ruby.
- Let go.
- It’s mine.
- You miserable barber.
It belongs to my robe.
It belongs to me, you understand?
- It’s mine.
- Have we lost our reason?
Are we children?
Isn’t there enough for three, 300, 3,000?
We’ll be the most powerful men in all India.
Here.
I can buy thousand of rubies like this
with my share.
[ Cackling ]
Buldeo, you are wise and good.
You saved my life.
You killed the cobra.
You are my friend.
Then stop quarrelling.
Load yourselves up.
We have to get out before nightfall.
[ Whimpers ]...
...[ Cackling ]...
...- Hurry. We’ve got to get out of here now.
- [ Growling ]...
...[ Snarling ]...
...[ Hissing ]...
...- [ Rifle Clicks ]
- [ Growls ]...
...[ Mowgli ] Thieves. Vultures.
Get out of the jungle.
Get out.
D-Did I hear what I heard?
The panther spoke
with the tongue of the boy.
Yes.
The boy spoke
with the tongue of the panther.
This place is bewitched.
Oh, the gold.
[ Animal Trilling ]...
...[ Chittering ]...
...This is the way.
Where’s the log? It was here.
How do we cross now?
We can wade through.
Wait.
There are crocodiles in this river.
What are you waiting for?
- It’s this way.
- No, no. We came past this tree.
- I tell you, it’s this way. Come on.
- No.
Quiet. Don’t argue, Barber.
You’re going the wrong way.
Give it to me.
- Wait here. Come on. Come on.
- [ Mowgli ] Look.
They are heading back to the Lost City.
- Here it is. There it is. Come on.
- Over there is right. Let’s go.
Come on.
Now I shall see
if Father Cobra spoke the truth.
If the thing is death...
...these men will die.
[ Gasps ]...
...- [ Stabs ]
- [ Barber Gasps ]...
...[ Stabbing Sounds ]...
...[ Shrieking ]...
...[ Animal Hoots ]...
...[ Bird Twittering ]...
...You saw it.
I only wanted to look at the gold.
[ Grunts ]...
...And he - he tried to kill me.
I had to do it, Buldeo.
I had to do it.
Naturally.
You -You must bear witness.
Please, you must bear witness, Buldeo.
[ Coins Rattling ]...
...[ Hooting ]...
...[ Wolf Howling, Growling ]...
...[ Howling Continues ]...
...Quiet, gray brother.
He tried to kill me, Buldeo.
You must bear witness.
I had to kill him.
[ Voice Breaking ] I had to kill him, Buldeo.
He -...
...[ Animal Squawking ]...
...[ Shouts ]...
...[ Animal Screeching ]...
...[ Buldeo, Pundit Grunting ]...
...[ Gasping, Shouts ]...
...[ Growling ]...
...Help. H-H-Help.
[ Screaming ] Help.
Did I hear someone call?
[ Animal Whooping ]...
...[ Whispers ] Now, gray brother...
...there is only one.
Bagheera, gray brother...
...chase him out of the jungle.
- Sing him home.
- [ Growls ]...
...[ Animal Whooping ]...
...[ Whooping Sound Continues ]...
...[ Low, Rhythmic Whooping ]...
...[ Roaring ]...
...- [ Whooping ]
- [ Animal Honking ]...
...- [ Gasping ]
- [ Growling ]...
...[ Loud Whooping ]...
...[ Hooting Continues ]...
...[ Growling Continues ]...
...[ Screeching, Whooping ]...
...[ Growling ]...
...- [ Howling ]
- [ Roaring ]...
...[ Trilling ]...
...[ Yipping ]...
...[ Roars ]...
...[ Animal Whooping ]...
...You grinning monster.
Change into any beast you will.
Wolf, panther...
...any beast you will.
I’m not afraid of you.
Change.
- Change.
- [ Animal Whooping ]...
...[ Animal Noises Continue ]...
...- [ Elephant Trumpets ]
- Scream.
- [ Growling, Hooting ]
- Scream, you witches of the forest.
[ Trumpeting, Screeching ]...
...- Scream.
- [ Animal Noises Continue ]...
...I’ll burn that mother witch Messua...
...and I’ll come back
with a hundred strong...
...and set fire to your jungle...
...when the east wind blows.
[ Trumpeting, Growling ]...
...I’ll burn you all.
- Burn you all.
- [ Roaring ]...
...Burn you all.
Hathi. Thou knowest the village
Of the Man-Pack that cast me out.
[ Quiet Trumpeting ]...
...They’re idle, senseless and cruel.
They do not kill the weaker for food...
...but for sport.
When they are full-fed, they would throw
their own breed into the Red Flower.
This I have seen.
It is not well that the Man-Pack
should live here anymore.
[ Trumpeting ]...
...Kill them? Why?
What good are their white bones to me?
We shall let the jungle in upon them...
...and give the village back
to the wild gourd vine.
They will burn us both.
Why did you fight them, Durga?
Why did you defend me?
It was I who brought him into the world.
He’s my son.
Aye, mistress.
You could have saved yourself, Durga.
No, mistress.
If you must leave the world tonight,
it is written that I shall go with you.
Buldeo is here. Look.
- Buldeo.
- [ All Shouting ]...
...What happened?
- Where is the pundit?
- Where is the barber?
Dead. Both dead.
Killed by the wolfboy.
But I know how to deal with him.
I’ll burn him.
Burn him up.
- I’ll burn him.
- [ Crowd Shouting ]...
...[ Excited Chattering ]...
...[ Chattering Continues ]...
...We’re all lost if the wind turns.
The jungle is burning.
Hurry up, Hathi.
[ Mahala ] Mowgli.
Where?s my mother?
What have you done with her?
They left Messua bound in her house.
They would not let me take her.
They said she was a witch
and that the fire would take her.
Now the same fire will take them.
But they were frightened, Mowgli.
Lead them, Mahala, to the little island
in the middle of the stream.
- Where we saw the elephants, Mowgli?
- Yes. The fire can’t touch you there.
Hurry. The wind is shifting.
[ Shouting ]...
...[ Trumpeting ]...
...Break the door, Hathi.
Break the door.
Push. Push.
Harder. Push.
I knew you would come.
See, Durga?
- [ Growling ]
- [ Growls ]...
...[ Howling ]...
... You’ll be safe among them now.
- But you, my son - Come with us.
Not while one little cub is in danger.
Now, go too.
Go on, Hathi. Go on. Go on.
Swim, gray brother. Follow me.
This way. Follow me.
Come on, Bagheera.
Come on, Hathi. Go on. Go on.
[ Roaring ]...
...Go on, Hathi. Go on. Go on.
[ Roars ]...
...[ Animal Screeching ]...
...Mowgli.
[ Bear Howling ]...
...Come back with us at last.
I am of the jungle.
Their lair is my lair.
Their trail is my trail.
Their fight is my fight.
[ Hathi Trumpets ]...
...Ahai.
He’s no longer my son.
[ Trumpets ]...
...He’s a godling of the woods.
[Buldeo Narrating]
So I didn't have my revenge after all.
I became no Mharaja...
...of a mighty city.
Even the little village burned to the ground.
In my struggle with the jungle...
...as you see, milords...
...I was beaten.
And then? What happened then?
What became of Mowgli
and your daughter?
And how did you escape from the fire?
That, memsahib...
...is another story.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org